A Guide to the Henly Fugate Business Records, 1879-1918
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Henly Fugate Business Records, 1879-1918
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Fugate, Henly, 1843-1913
Ms1978-007
5 Cubic Feet 4 boxes
This collection contains business records and personal financial records generated by Henly Fugate.
4 Boxes; 5.0 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Henly Fugate Business Records were donated to the Special Collections in 1978.
Biographical Information
Born on May 22, 1843, in Claiborne County, Tennessee, Henly Fugate rose to the level of captain in the army of the Confederate States of America (company A of the 63rd Regiment, Tennessee Infantry). Following the Civil War, Fugate moved to Abingdon, Virginia in 1873 where he started and operated businesses involving lumber and coal. He also served as a trustee of the Stonewall Jackson Institute and the Abingdon Male Academy until his death in 1913.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of correspondence and records regarding the business concerns of Henly Fugate. These businesses included Trigg, Fugate, and Company (lumber); H. Fugate and Company (lumber); and the Raven Red Ash Coal Company (coal).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series: Series I, Trigg, Fugate, and Company; Series II, H. Fugate and Company; Series III, Raven Red Ash Coal Company; Series IV, Personal Records. Files within each series are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Index Terms
Persons:
Fugate, Henly, 1843-1913
Corporate Names:
Trigg, Fugate, and Company
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South
Contents List
- Series I: Trigg, Fugate, and Company
  - Correspondence, A-B, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Correspondence, C, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Correspondence, D-G, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Correspondence, H, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Correspondence, J-L, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Correspondence, M-P, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Correspondence, R-S, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Correspondence, T-Y, 1895-March 22, 1896 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Correspondence, A-B, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Correspondence, C, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Correspondence, D, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Correspondence, E-G, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Correspondence, H-K, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Correspondence, L-O, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Correspondence, P-S, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Correspondence, T-Y, March 23-May 27, 1896 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Correspondence, A-B, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Correspondence, C, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Correspondence, C, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Correspondence, D-H, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Correspondence, J-N, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Correspondence, P-V, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Correspondence, W, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Correspondence, Y, May 28-August 9, 1896 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Daybook, June 27-October 22, 1887 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Daybook, October 22, 1887-April 4, 1888 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Daybook, April 15, 1888-February 27, 1889 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Daybook, February 28, 1889-January 27, 1890 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Daybook, March 14, 1894-December 16, 1896 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Letter Book, January 23-May 31, 1895 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Letter Book, May 31-September 24, 1895 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Letter Book, September 24, 1895-February 4, 1896 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Letter Book, February 4-May 11, 1896 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Water Rights, Holston River, 1909-11 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Ledger, 1887 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Series II: Henly Fugate and Company Records
  - Correspondence, A-F, 1903-12 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Correspondence, G-M, 1902-13 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Correspondence, N-S, 1908-12 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Correspondence, T-Y, 1896-1912 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Financial Records, 1907-09 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Ledger, 1885-87 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Ledger, 1881-89 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Lumber Camp Photographs, n.d. (Box-folder 3:10)
- Series III: Raven Red Ash Coal Company Records
  - Correspondence, 1909-13 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Financial Records, 1909 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Financial Records, 1910 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Financial Records, 1911 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Financial Records, 1912 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Financial Records, 1913 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Financial Records, 1918 (Box-folder 3:17)
- Series IV: Personal Records
  - Financial Records, 1879-1915 (Box-folder 3:18)